# Arijit Bhattacharya 🕡 Featured

Software Developer seeking assignment in Software Development,Software Application Development,Project Management,Requirement Gathering,Software Testing,Database Design,jQuery,JavaScript,MySQL,Java,CSS,AJAX,Laravel,Core Java,Multithreading,PHP



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Electron Bridge Pvt Ltd Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Noida Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Software Application Development, Project

Management, Requirement Gathering, Software Testing, Database

Design, ¡Query, JavaScript, MySQL, Java, CSS, AJAX, Laravel, Core Java, Multithreading, PHP

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

### **Summary**

Nearly 6 years professional Internet industry experience as a Software Developer in web development, Database Design, integration, implementation, software development, testin

Skills - Expert / Advanced

jQuery , JavaScript, MySQL, Java , CSS 3, AJAX , Laravel , Core Java, Multithreading , Collections , JDBC Core PHP, Codelgniter

Skills - Competent

Java8, JPA, Spring, Hibernate, Data Structures, Tomcat, Apache, Servlet, JSP, JSF, Python, Django, Flask, Angular7 Object Oriented PHP

Skills - Moderate Exposure

Web Services (REST), Maven, JSF, Glassfish, Tiles, UML, Spring Boot, Velocity, MySQL, Postgres, , Oracle SQ

## Work Experience

Electron Bridge Pvt Ltd as Software Developer

May 2017 to Till Date

Maintain Existing Web based Wholesale Application along with upload CSV Files using PHP and PostgreSQL using python 3.8, Numpy, pandas.

Maintain Lime-T dialer dashboard using Java and PostgreSQL and some section are updated using python and pandas. Develop Aiwa Mobile Recharge App using Spring Boot Rest API Microservices along with admin dashboard using PostgreSQL database.

Develop ask now application using spring boot in backend as Rest API and frontend as Angular7 along with PostgreSQL database.

FIEO Import and Export Excel Sheets using Java8, Hibernate and PostgreSQL database as backend script.

#### Apex Software Pvt Ltd as Software Developer

Nov 2016 to May 2017

Manage Billing Software(Web based) using Java and MySQL. Maintain Reporting Section were developed using Java

#### CTR Industry Pvt Ltd as Management Information Assistant

Feb 2014 to Nov 2015

Manage Email-reminder Software using Java Work as Backend in MRP System Software.

Manage Oracle database using Bast Register (for calculation of Service Tax).

Import Export CSV files for concerned departments are sent from one server to another by organization email using Java.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Received a promotion letter from company as Associate Software Developer.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (pcm) from Gurukul Kangri university, Haridwar in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers) from gurukul kangri university,haridwar in 2013

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Eclipse IDE,VS Code	
jQuery , JavaScript, MySQL, Java	
CSS 3, AJAX , Laravel , Core Java	
Multithreading, Collections, JDBC CorePHP	
CODEIGNITER	
Java8, JPA, Spring, Hibernate	
Data Structures, Tomcat, Apache Web Server	
Servlet, JSP, JSF, Python, Django	
Flask, Angular7 Object Oriented PHP	

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				

#### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time